

Hieu (Ian) Vu

AI Engineer

Hieu M. Vu vmhieu in lone17

SUMMARY

I consider myself a novice trying to get out of Dunning-Kruger's Valley of Despair, an individual who is intellectually curious and passionate about making even the slightest meaningful impact. I have been working in the industry for over four years, focusing on Information Extraction on business documents using techniques from Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing. However, my research interest does not lie within said domains. I am open to any interesting topic as I am driven by the urge of contributing to the greater good and am easily intrigued by technological

- 4 years of experience in AI/DL, mostly focused on Document Image Understanding.
- 1 year of experience in Data Science, focused on geophysical data.
- Co-authored 3 papers on Information Extraction.
- Bachelor of Computer Science Highest Ranking Graduate.

EXPERIENCE

Cinnamon AI

AI Researcher/Engineer

Nov 2018 — Present

Hanoi, Vietnam

- Build Document Intelligence technologies
 - Conducted researches, applied state-of-the-art methods to serve client projects.
 - Co-authored **3 papers** on Information Extraction.
 - Worked on Information Extraction for Visually-rich Documents with limited data using language models, increased the f1-score by 2% - 7% on several client data sets.
 - Worked on Document-object Detection and Localization on images, over 85% IoU score achieved.
 - Worked on **Document Image Classification**, over 85% accuracy achieved on a data set with 20+ classes.
 - Worked on **Object Detection on Visually-rich Documents**, such as stamps and bullet point symbols.
 - Worked on **Data Synthesis/Augmentation** using image processing techniques for overcoming data shortage.
 - Other problems worked on: Text segmentation, printed/handwriting OCR, handled AI flow on client projects, contributed to internal libraries.
- Contribute to the Internal Data Management System
 - Developed **synchronization and local version control features** for the CLI tool.
 - Initiated and took charge of **data standardization**: making data from client projects be collectively re-useable for RnD purposes.
 - Participated in system design and feature planning.
 - Aligned requests and expectations of different user groups (RnD members and DataOps members).
- Supported RnD Business alignment, aiming toward creating business-oriented solutions.
- Other tasks: Conducting/Facilitating technical sharing sessions; Training/Mentoring.
- Tools and technologies
 - Mainly used: Python, Pytorch, Tensorflow/Keras, Transformers (Hugging Face), Git, OpenCV, Scikit-learn LATEX.
 - Also familiar with: DVC, Docker, Jenkins, CircleCI, KubeFlow, Elasticsearch.
 - Environments: GCP, AWS, Linux, Windows.

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Aug 2017 — Sep 2019

IOT Lab, University of Engineering and Technology - Vietnam National University, Hanoi

Hanoi, Vietnam

- Worked on the Well Insight platform
 - Built predictive models for geophysical data using machine learning and statical methods.
 - Contributed to the Machine Learning module of the Well Insight platform.
 - Worked on: Facies/rock type classification; Time series prediction on well-logs data; Permeability regression; Integrated Prediction Error Filter Analysis (INPEFA) curve calculation; Cumulative and Federated learning for well-logs data.
- Tools and technologies: Python, Keras/Tensorflow, OpenCV, Scikit-learn, XGBoost, Javascript.

PUBLICATIONS

- Nguyen, Bao-Sinh, Tien Dung Le, **Hieu M Vu**, Tuan-Anh D Nguyen, Minh-Tien Nguyen, and Hung Le (2022). "Improving Document Image Understanding with Reinforcement Finetuning". In: *arXiv* preprint *arXiv*:2209.12561. Accepted to ICONIP 2022.
- Son, Nguyen Hong, **Hieu M Vu**, Tuan-Anh D Nguyen, and Minh-Tien Nguyen (2022). "Jointly Learning Span Extraction and Sequence Labeling for Information Extraction from Business Documents". In: *arXiv* preprint arXiv:2205.13434. Accepted to IJCNN 2022 (Oral).
- 3 Nguyen, Tuan-Anh D, **Hieu M Vu**, Nguyen Hong Son, and Minh-Tien Nguyen (2021). "A Span Extraction Approach for Information Extraction on Visually-Rich Documents". In: *International Conference on Document Analysis and Recognition*. Best Paper Award, DIL ICDAR 2021). Springer, pp. 353–363.
- 4 **Vu**, **Hieu M** and Diep Thi-Ngoc Nguyen (2020). "Revising FUNSD dataset for key-value detection in document images". In: *arXiv* preprint *arXiv*:2010.05322.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Degree, Computer Science (Honours Programme)

University of Engineering and Technology - Vietnam National University, Hanoi

GPA: 3.83/4.00

- Highest Ranking Graduate
- Merit for Excellent Graduation Certificate recipient.
- Excellent Thesis Defence Certificate recipient.
- Excellent Student Certificate recipient (3 times).
- Academic Encouragement Scholarship recipient (4 times).

Honours and Awards

Best Paper Award Sep 2021

ICDAR 2021, Workshop on Document Images and Language

Paper title: A Span Extraction Approach for Information Extraction on Visually-Rich Documents
Accepted for oral presentation and awarded the Best Paper Award at Workshop on Document Images and Language, ICDAR 2021.

Top 4 Zalo AI Challenge 2018 - Voice Track

Sep 2018

Zalo, VNG Corporation (Individual participant)

Finished at 4th place on the Private Leaderboard of the Voice Gender/Accent Classification challenge. Zalo AI Challenge 2018 is a Kaggle-like competition hosted by Zalo - one of the biggest tech companies in Vietnam. The competition attracted over 700 teams competed in 3 challenges.

Certificate of Highest Ranking Graduate

University of Engineering and Technology - Vietnam National University, Hanoi Awarded to students graduate with the highest GPA amongst the graduating class.

(Google Scholar profile).

SKILLS

Programming	Python, Git, IATEX, MarkDown, Java, C/C++, SQL, SPRQL.
Tools and Library	Pytorch, Transformers (Hugging Face) , Tensorflow/Keras, Notebook, Github, OpenCV, Scikit-learn, Docker, LibROSA.
AI Domains	Information Extraction , Document Intelligence, Document Understanding, Data Science, Natural Language Processing, Computer Vision.
Environments	GCP, AWS, Linux, Windows.
Languages	Vietnamese (native), English (fluent), Japanese (JLPT N4).
${f Misc}$	Problem Solving, Attentive to detail, Presentation, Communication, Academic Research

Last updated: 09-Dec-2022

PROJECTS

Voice Gender/Accent Classification

Zalo AI Challenge 2018 🗹

Aug 2018 — Sep 2018



- 4th place on the Private Leaderboard, achieved 79.208% accuracy.
- Individual participant, participated only during the last 10 days/1 month+ of the competition.
- Problem description: Classify the speaker's voice in a recording (typically under 3 seconds) by gender(male/female) and regional accent (northern/central/southern).
- About the competition: Zalo AI Challenge 2018 is a Kaggle-like competition hosted by Zalo one of the biggest tech companies in Vietnam. The competition attracted over 700 teams competed in 3 challenges.

Electric Meter OCR

University Coursework Project





- Achieved **0.08** on edit distance while having the size of just under **10MB** and processing time of under **0.3** seconds per image on a normal laptop.
- Problem description: Extract the value on the dial from images of electric meters. The solution is meant to be used in embedded hardwares.

OUTREACH

Cinnamon AI Global Bootcamp 2022

Mentoring

- Mentored a group of 4 students. The team eventually won the 2nd prize for their graduation project.
- (These kids are amazing, far more gifted than I am.)
- Contributed to syllabus design, contributed questions to the entrance test, interviewed candidates.

Cinnamon AI Taiwan Bootcamp 2020

Teaching/Mentoring

- Prepared materials and gave lectures on Language modelling and Transformers to a class of 15 students, most of them hold a Master degree or are Master students. Also mentored a group of 3.
- Contributed to syllabus design, interviewed candidates.